# RUSSELL CULVER

Toronto, ON 905-802-3102 russellc@sequranet.com

in linkedin.com/in/russell-culver-9318969a

## Full Stack Developer with Finance & Business Competencies

Summary	7
oumman y	,

Technical focus with finance and business experience, is the result of founding and running a start-up for nearly five years. Technical expertise ranges from cloud infrastructure design to Test Driven Development on both front and back-end projects. Extensive experience working with Ubuntu, CentOS, datacentre networking, Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Bootstrap, AJAX, Hyper-V and custom enterprise-scale storage platforms. Financial experience developing equity trading models using multiple strategies and investment vehicles. Thorough understanding of technical analysis, indicators and risk mitigation. Junior level machine-learning experience in a financial environment.

### Work experience

#### 2013 - Present

### Founder, CTO

### Seguranet Data Solutions Inc. Toronto, ON.

Identified niche market, researched sector, assembled team, developed turn-key product, delivered to market.

- Designed, built and implemented software and hardware platform that currently manages over 2 million digital health assets.
- Comprehensive understanding of all business operations, with a focus on technical aspects.
- Led development on all three integrated software solutions (Client, Server, Web App), meeting PHIPA and PIPEDA digital compliance standards for offsite data storage.
- Led design for entire server infrastructure / network / datacentre solution.
- Experience sourcing local and remote team members, leading development teams and projects.
- Assisted in development of partner and re-seller programs, and the technical adjustments to account for large-scale on-boarding.
- Routinely managed financial and liability aspects of business operations.

# Held additional roles with MCI Automation, CoreSoft, Cyntek Industrial, Colenet Technical Services on a consultation basis.

### 2012 - 2013

### Project Development

### ABELSoft Inc. Burlington, ON.

Initially brought on as a summer student, I quickly became involved in numerous projects such as the Ontario Laboratories Information System (OLIS) implementation, troubleshooting and deployment.

- Was responsible for on-boarding over 200 end users to ABELMed's OLIS integration.
- Was responsible for calculation of corporate compensation on a per-physician basis via eHealth.
- Assisted in early development of ABELMed / ABELDent Portal.

### Education

2010 - 2013

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Political Science, American Studies (Dbl. Major, IPR).

University of Toronto St. George

Member of Varsity Football Team 2010-2011, 2012-2013.

Skills

Hardware/Systems

Windows Server, Hyper-V, Linux Server Distros, Firewalls, Enterprise Networking, Largescale storage platforms.

Languages

Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, PHP, ORMs, .NET

Finance

Equity Risk Assessment & Mitigation, Model Design, Technical Analysis.

Machine Learning

Probabilistic machine learning, application of linear regression, KNN, inefficiency identification.